Sayed Nabil

Full-stack Developer

+20 1029465001 <u>sayedOnabil@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/sayedOnabil</u> <u>github.com/sayedOnabil</u> Giza, Egypt

Technically-minded and highly analytical professional with experience in software development and programming. Proven success in evaluating user requirements and developing/presenting technical solutions accordingly. Expert in assessing and troubleshooting complex technical issues and updating systems and applications. Skilled at building and maintaining long-term professional relationships with clients and staff. Active learner, always striving to grasp new technologies and procedures. Possess strong communication, planning, and analytical problem-solving skills.

Live Portfolio → https://sayed0nabil.github.io/portofolio/

Work Experience

Vodafone Intelligent Solutions, Cairo, Egypt

Software Developer in UK market

Designed and implemented new features and applications. Estimated user requirements, devised code, and applied integration tests. Created modules and solutions to streamline business operations.

Collaborated with solution designers to analyze backlog items. Coded and debugged complex technical

issues and cases.

Alexbank, Cairo, Egypt

2020 - 2020 (6 months)

2020 - Present

Software Application Developer

worked on banking business cases and interacting with the IBM CRM system

Freelancer, Cairo, Egypt

2018 - 2019 (1 year)

Full Stack Developer

worked on full stack projects using react.js, node.js and mongodb

Additional Experience

Trainee, ITI, Cairo, Egypt, 2019 – 2020 (9 months) [Enterprise web application Track(java technologies)]

Taken comprehensive courses for java technologies and worked on a lot of projects

Trainee, ITI, Zagazig university 2018 (3 months) [front-end Track]

Applied Front-end web technologies, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular

Education

Bachelor of Computers and Informatics in Computer Science

Zagazig University, Egypt, 2019

GPA: Very Good

Graduation Project Name: Optical Mark Recognition Designer

Graduation GPA: Excellent

Technical Proficiencies

Front-end Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript ,AJAX , Typescript, Bootstrap, JQuery, JQuery-mobile,

Angular, React

Back-end Technologies: Java SE, Servlets, JSP, JSF, EJB, JPA, Hibernate, Web Services [REST, SOAP],

Spring [Core, MVC, Data, Boot, cloud], Junit, Mockito, Docker, Maven,

Microservices, Apache Kafka, ELK Stack

Database: Oracle Database, MySQL, MongoDB

Conceptual Knowledge: Object Orientation Concepts, Database designing concepts, Object-relational

mapping, Design patterns, Agile methodology, UML designing concepts,

Aspect-oriented programming, Document-based database, NoSQL